DEAN: Dad wants us to pick up
where he left off.
Saving people, hunting things.
The family business.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
REPORTER [ON TV]: Their attacker,
a white male, 24 to 30 years of age.
-Not a good picture.
-Shape-shifter?
DEAN: Every culture has a shape-shifter.
-Something that looks like anyone?
Freeze. Stay on your knees.
-He's been held on suspicion of murder.
-Murder?
WOMAN: We're here downtown in front
of the City Bank of Milwaukee...
...and though a short exchange
of gunfire occurred minutes ago...
...police and SWAT teams
maintain position...
...as we enter the third hour
of this intense standoff.
Authorities estimate as many as 10
hostages are being held inside the bank.
No word as yet on the identity
of the suspects or--
COP 1: Coming out. Hold your position!
-Something's happening.
I think they're opening the door.
Roger, are you getting this?
COP [ON RADIO]: Hostage coming out.
Stand down. Stand down. Hold fire.
HENRY:
Hey, don't shoot. Don't shoot. Please.
DEAN: No, no, no. Don't even
think about it. Get the hell back.
HENRY:
Please, don't shoot.
So, what's it like, being an FBI guy?
Well, it's dangerous.
Yeah.
And the secrets we gotta keep.
Oh, God, the secrets.
But mostly, it's lonely.
-I so know what you mean.
-Yeah.
Helena was our head buyer. She--
She was family, you know?
She said it herself.
Every Christmas party she said
we were the only family she had.
There were no signs
that she'd do this?
No, I still can't believe it, even now.
That night, Helena came back
to the store after closing.
Cleaned out all the display cases
and the safe.
Edgar, our night watchman,
he caught her in the act.
He didn't know what to do.
He'd known her for years.
He called me at home.
And that's when she took his gun?
She shot him in the face.
I heard him die...
...over the phone.
Any idea what
her motive could've been?
What motive? It makes no sense.
Why steal all those diamonds, jewelry,
then what, just dump it somewhere?
Just hide it and then go home and--
She killed herself?
The cops said she dropped a hairdryer
in the bath and fried herself.
They should know, right?
Yeah.
Well, thanks, Frannie.
Think that's all I need.
Really? I mean, because I've got more.
You know, if you wanted to
interview me...
...sometime, in private?
Yeah. Yeah, I think that's a good idea.
You're a true patriot, you really are.
Why don't you write your number down?
So you never saw the security camera
footage yourself, then.
The police, they took all the tapes,
first thing.
Of course they did.
Look at your file, this is it.
-Frigging cops.
-They're just doing their job.
No, they're doing our job.
Only they don't know it, so they suck at it.
-Talk to me about this bank.
-Milwaukee National Trust.
-It was hit a month ago.
-Same M.O. as the jewelry store?
Inside job, long-time employee.
The never-in-a-million-years type.
Dude robs the bank, then goes home
and supposedly commits suicide.
DEAN: Reznick was the guard on duty?
-He was beaten unconscious...
-...by the teller who heisted the place.
-God.
Yeah.
Mr. Reznick?
Ronald Reznick?
Son of a--
FBI, Mr. Reznick.
Let me see the badge.
Already gave my statement
to the police.
Ronald, just some things
about your statement.
We want some clarification on it.
-You read it?
-Sure did.
-Come to listen to what I gotta say?
-That's why we're here.
Well, come on in.
None of the cops ever called me back.
Not after I told them
what was really going on.
They all thought I was crazy.
First off, Juan Morales never robbed
the Milwaukee National Trust.
That I guarantee.
Me and Juan were friends.
He used to come back to the bank on
my night shifts and we'd play cards.
So you let him into the bank that night.
After hours.
The thing I let into the bank...
...wasn't Juan.
I mean it had his face,
but it wasn't his face.
Every detail was perfect
but too perfect.
Like if a doll maker made it,
like, if I was talking to a big Juan doll.
-A "Juan doll"?
-Look.
This wasn't the only time.
There was this jewelry store too.
And the cops and you guys, I mean,
you just won't see it.
Both crimes were pulled
by the same thing.
And what's that, Mr. Reznick?
Chinese been working on them
and the Russians before that.
Part man, part machine.
Like the Terminator but the kind
that can change itself.
Make itself look like others.
-Like from T2.
-Exactly.
See, not just a robot.
More of a "mandroid."
A mandroid?
What makes you so sure about this,
Ronald?
See, I made copies
of all the security tapes.
I knew once the cops got them
they'd be buried. Here.
Now watch.
Watch.
Watch him, watch, watch.
See? Look, there it is.
You see, he's got the laser eyes.
Cops said it was
some kind of reflected light.
Some kind of "camera flare." Okay?
Ain't no damn camera flare.
They say I'm a post-trauma case.
So what? Bank goes and fires me?
It don't matter.
The mandroid is still out there.
The law won't hunt this thing down...
...I'll do it myself.
You see, this thing, it kills the real person.
Makes it look like a suicide.
Then it, like, morphs into the person.
Cases the job for a while till it knows
the take is fat...
...then finds its opening.
These robberies, they're grouped
together. So I figure...
...the mandroid is holed up
in the middle.
Underground maybe. I don't know.
Maybe that's where it recharges
its mandroid batteries.
Okay.
I want you to listen very carefully.
Because I'm about to tell you
the gods' honest truth about all of this.
There's no such thing as mandroids.
There's nothing evil or inhuman going on
out there. Just people.
Nothing else, you understand?
-The laser eyes--
-Just a camera flare.
I know you don't wanna believe it, but
your friend robbed the bank and that's it.
Get out of my house!
-Now.
-Sure.
First things first.
Man, that has got to be the kicker,
straight up.
You tell that poor son of a bitch that--
What did you say?
Remand the tapes that he copied?
Classified evidence of an ongoing
investigation? That's messed up.
What, are you pissed at me?
I think it's creepy
how good of a fed you are.
We could've thrown the guy a bone.
He did some pretty good legwork.
-Mandroid?
-Except for the mandroid part.
I liked him.
He's not that different from us.
-People think we're crazy.
-He's not a hunter.
He's a guy who
stumbled onto something.
If he went up against this,
he'd get torn apart.
Better to stay in the dark
and stay alive.
Yeah, I guess.
Shape-shifter.
Just like back at St. Louis.
Same retinal reaction to video.
Eyes flare at the camera.
-I hate those frigging things.
-You think I don't?
One didn't turn into you
and frame you for murder.
Look, if this shifter's anything
like the one in Missouri--
Then Ronald's right.
They like to lair up underground.
Preferably the sewer.
All the robberies are connected
so far to the sewer main layout.
There's one more bank lined up
on that sewer main.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
HENRY: We haven't had any flags
go up on our system yet.
DEAN:
No, this is a glitch in the overall grid.
Just wanna make sure the branch
monitors are kosher.
-Better to be safe than sorry.
-That's the plan.
Alrighty.
You guys need anything else?
No, we'll be in and out before
you know it. A routine check.
Okey-dokey.
-I like him. He says okey-dokey.
-What if he's the shifter?
Then we follow him home and put a
silver bullet through his chest plate.
Okay. Got any popcorn?
Well, looks like Mr. Okey-dokey...
...is okey-dokey.
Maybe we jumped the gun on this,
Dean.
We don't even know it's here.
Maybe we should just go on back
to the sewers and--
We're supposed to be looking for eyes.
-I'm getting there.
-Oh, yeah?
Wait a minute.
-Hello, freak.
-Got him.
DEAN:
Sam.
What?
Hello, Ronald.
RONALD:
This is not a robbery.
[GUNFIRE]
Everybody on the floor now.
RONALD:
Get down, damn it.
Come on, on the floor, on the floor.
In the middle.
On the floor in the middle.
In the middle, on the floor. Come on.
Hurry up. Come on.
And you said we shouldn't bring guns.
I didn't know
this was gonna happen.
I'll do the talking.
I don't think he likes you.
Now there's only one way in
or out of here and I chained it up.
So nobody's leaving, you understand?
DEAN:
Hey, buddy.
Now, why don't you calm down?
Just calm down.
What the--?
You.
-Get on the floor now.
-Okay, we're doing that.
Just don't shoot anybody.
Especially us.
I knew it. As soon as you two left.
You ain't FBI. Who are you?
Who are you working for?
The Men in Black?
-You working for the mandroid?
-We're not.
You shut up! I ain't talking to you,
I don't like you!
Fair enough.
RONALD: Get over there, frisk them down,
make sure they got no weapons. Go.
Now what have we here?
I'm not gonna walk in here naked.
RONALD:
Get back down.
No, no, no, no!
You don't wanna hurt anybody,
but it will happen if you keep waving that.
-Why don't you let these people go?
-No! I told you...
...if nobody's gonna stop this thing,
then I gotta do it myself.
-We believe you. That's why we're here.
-You don't believe me.
Nobody believes me.
How could they?
Come here.
What? No.
You got the gun, boss, you're calling
the shots. I wanna tell you something.
It's the bank manager.
What?
Why do you think
we got these getups?
We were monitoring the cameras.
We saw the manager. We saw his eyes.
-His laser eyes?
-Yes.
No. We're running out of time.
We gotta find him before he changes.
Like I'm gonna listen to you.
You're a damn liar.
I'll shoot you. Get down!
Take me, take me with you as a hostage.
But we gotta act fast.
The longer we sit here,
the more time he has to change.
Look at me, man.
I believe you.
You're not crazy.
There really is something
inside this bank.
All right.
You come with me.
But everyone else gets in the vault!
[WHISTLES]
Come on. Move, move.
RONALD:
Come on, move.
Move, move. And you lock it up.
It's okay, everyone.
Just stay cool.
RONALD:
Spin that. Spin that door.
Who is that man?
He's my brother.
He is so brave.
Check behind the desk.
Ugh!
Ah! Ah!
What the hell is that?
Oh, great.
When it changes form, it sheds its old skin,
so now it could be anybody.
It's so....
It's so weird.
-Its robot skin is so lifelike.
-Let's get something straight.
It's not a mandroid.
-It's a shape-shifter. Yeah.
-Shape-shifter?
It's human, more or less.
Has human drives.
In this case, it's money.
But it generates its own skin.
Shape it to match someone else's features.
-Tall or short, male--
-It kills someone and takes their place?
-Kills or doesn't, I don't think it matters.
-What are you doing?
Nice.
Remember the old werewolf stories?
Pretty much came from these guys.
Silver is the only thing
I've seen that hurts them.
Come on, Ronald.
COP 1: Come on, come on, let's move.
COP 2: Move out of here.
COP 3: All right, come on,
let's hustle, hustle, hustle.
-How we doing?
-Another day in paradise.
-No one's come out yet?
-This guy locked himself in.
The first thing he did.
All right. Cut the power.
-Are you nuts?
-That's just it.
I'm not nuts.
I mean, I was so scared that I was
losing my marbles. But this is real.
I mean, I was right. Except for
the mandroid thing. Thank you.
Yeah, don't mention it.
Damn it. No, no, no.
What? What is it?
They cut the power.
It's their way of saying hi.
-Who?
-Cops.
The cops?
You weren't exactly
a smooth criminal about this.
You didn't secure the security guard,
He probably called them.
-I didn't think to--
-Hang on. Let's breathe, all right?
They probably got us surrounded.
They cut the power to the cameras.
No way of telling who the shape-shifter is.
It's not looking good, Ron.
[THUMP]
Did you hear that?
SHERRI:
Has your brother always been so...
...wonderful?
I mean, staring down that gun.
And the way he played into
that psycho's crazy head...
...telling him what he wanted to hear?
-He's like a real hero or something.
-Yeah.
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
-You saved us. You saved us.
-I just found a few more.
Come on, everybody, let's go.
Let's go.
-What are you doing?
-Sam?
Ronald and I need to talk to you.
It shed its skin again. We don't know.
Could be in the halls, the vault.
Great.
-Dean, you are wanted by the police.
-Yeah.
Even if we do find this damn thing,
how are we gonna get out of here?
One problem at a time.
I'm gonna do a sweep of the place,
find any stragglers.
Once we got everybody,
we play a game of Find the Freaks.
So here.
I found another one of these for you.
Stay here, make sure
Ronald doesn't hurt anybody.
-Help him manage the situation.
-Help him manage?
Are you insane?
-This isn't going the way we wanted.
-Understatement!
But if we let the cops in now,
Ronald gets arrested, we get arrested.
The shifter gets away.
Probably never find it again, okay?
Ron.
Out of the light.
[CHUCKLES]
-Seriously?
DEAN: Ron's game plan was a bad plan.
It's a little bit of a crazy plan. But right
now crazy is the only game in town.
Hi, Ronald.
[THUMP]
[CREAKING]
I'm gonna keep this open,
get you some fresh air in there.
But no one leaves this vault.
[PHONE RINGING]
I don't understand.
Why are you helping him?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
-Hello?
-I think I gotta get out of here.
-Sir, I'm sorry but you gotta stay put.
RONALD: What?
-What do you mean, demands?
-Ron.
-Hang up.
-I'm not a bank robber.
HENRY: I gotta get out of here.
-You can't leave.
I'm kind of a crime fighter.
SHERRI: Henry, just breathe, okay?
-Ronald!
Hey!
-Look--
RONALD: No, I'm acting alone.
-Ronald?
SAMPSON: Hey.
-The less the cops know, the better.
-This dude's having a heart attack.
Great. Could be our guy,
could be a trick.
-Are you just gonna let the man die?
-No one's dying here.
Cover the door.
Can you tell me how many hostages?
One could be having heart trouble.
You need to send in a paramedic.
-Just stay calm, we'll have you out--
-Send in a paramedic.
Don't try anything else. Please.
Paramedic? Guy don't have time.
Listen, I'm sorry. Okay? I am.
But nobody's getting out.
He's dying right in front of you.
HENRY:
Help.
Come on, man.
You gotta unlock the front door.
We've gotta get him out of here.
RONALD:
Both of you, stay where you are.
You know, Ronald...
...he's right. We gotta get this man outside.
Come on.
SAMPSON:
Yeah, I'll help you.
Oh, I got him. It's cool.
-Thanks.
HENRY: Thank you.
SAM: Watch your step. Sure.
-Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
DEAN:
Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
You got the gun, man.
Whatever.
RONALD:
Stop, come back here.
[INAUDIBLE]
Get down, Ron!
DISPATCHER [ON RADIO]: All units
be advised, we have five to 12 hostages...
...in the City Bank of Milwaukee
Bradley Center.
MAN 1:
Yes, go. Go, go.
Here.
Take care of the guard.
I'm going after the shifter.
Sorry, Ron.
You did a real good job tracking this thing.
You really did.
-Oh! Please don't hurt us.
-You shouldn't be back here.
You're in danger.
Now go back to the vault. Now.
DISPATCHER:
Hostages in the City Bank....
DEAN:
This will all be over soon.
DISPATCHER:
Stand by for further.
DEAN: Everything's gonna be all right.
-Hey, don't shoot. Don't shoot, please.
DEAN:
No, no, no. Back up.
Don't even think about it.
HENRY:
Please don't shoot.
DEAN:
Son of a bitch.
COP 1:
Moving in. Moving in.
I said, get back, now!
One of the hostages, he seems to
have taken over the situation.
Excuse me?
Okay. Go, go.
Get down.
We are so screwed.
[PHONE RINGING]
-Yeah?
-He's slipped his skin.
-What?
-Yeah, bastard shifts fast.
Faster than the one in St. Louis.
It's like playing a shell game.
Could be anybody again.
-The employees are out of the vault.
-You search every inch.
I'll round everybody up.
[SIRENS WAILING]
-Crap.
-What?
The feds are here.
Oh, crap.
-Lieutenant Robards.
-Yeah.
Special Agent Henriksen.
Let me guess. You're lead dog now,
but you'd just love my full cooperation.
I don't give a rat's ass what you do.
Get a doughnut and bang your wife.
What I do need is your SWAT team,
locked and loaded.
Listen, agent,
something's not right about this.
It's--
-It's not going down like a usual heist.
-That's because it isn't one.
You have no idea
what you're dealing with, do you?
There's a monster in that bank, Robards.
And I thought you were
one of the good guys.
-What's your name?
-Why would you care?
My name is Dean.
I'm Sherri.
Hi, Sherri.
Everything's gonna be all right.
This will all be over soon, okay?
[PHONE RINGS]
-Yeah.
-This is Special Agent Victor Henriksen.
Yeah, listen, I'm not
in the negotiating mood.
Me neither. It's my job to bring you in.
-Alive's a bonus, but not necessary.
-Kind of harsh for a fed, don't you think?
You're not the typical suspect,
are you, Dean?
I want you and Sam out here, unarmed.
Or we come in. And yes, I know about
Sam too. Bonnie to your Clyde.
Well, that part's true.
But how'd you know we were here?
Go screw yourself. That's how.
It's become my job to know about you.
I've been looking for you for weeks.
I know about the murder in St. Louis,
the Houdini act in Baltimore.
I know about the desecrations,
the thefts. I know about your dad.
-You don't know crap about my dad.
-Ex-Marine, raised his kids on the road.
Cheap motels, backwoods cabins.
Real paramilitary survivalist type.
I just can't get a handle
on what type of wacko he was.
White supremacist, Timmy McVeigh,
tomato, tomato.
You got no right
talking about my dad like that.
-He was a hero.
-Yeah. Right. Sure sounds like it.
You have one hour to make a decision
or we come, full automatic.
[PHONE HANGS UP]
Scramble your men.
Five minutes, then we go in.
What? Henriksen,
they've let out one hostage so far.
-They've hurt no one.
-You don't know these Winchesters.
-They're dangerous and expertly trained.
-We can't risk all those people.
-Trust me. Dean's a risk to them.
-This is crazy.
Crazy's in there and I just hung up on it.
Damn it.
-Hey.
We got a bit of a problem outside.
We got a problem in here.
Sherri? We're gonna let you go.
What?
-Why me?
-As a show of good faith to the feds.
I think I'd rather stay here
with the others.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to insist.
I thought you were letting me go.
[SHERRI SCREAMING]
Is that community theater
or are you naturally like this?
This is the last time
you become anybody. Ever.
SHERRI:
No. Oh, God. Oh....
[THUMP]
Dean, wait.
What's the advantage of this plan?
I mean, fainting now
wouldn't help it survive.
Hmm.
[WINDOW SHATTERS]
[DEAN GRUNTING]
SHERRI:
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Get her out of here. Now!
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
I work here. I work here.
Please get me out.
Please get me out of here.
COP 1:
Freeze!
Let me see your hands.
Gross.
COP 1: Clear in here.
COP 2: Clear. Move.
COP 3: Clear.
COP 4: Clear. Go.
COP 1:
Clear. Move.
COP 2:
Male, African-American. Goner.
I'm telling you, man.
I just walked her out of the bank.
She must have a twin sister
or something.
COP 1:
Clear.
Sir, my team said it's secure.
They're gone.
You tell your team to tear it apart.
-Ducts, ceiling, furnace, everything.
-That's not necessary.
Why not?
[SIGHS]
We are so screwed.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]